

Rabi' Ibrahim Software Development Engineer

ribra92@icloud.com

+962797048292

Amman, Jordan ♀

rabiibrahim.github.io

...

linkedin.com/in/rabiibrahim in

A software engineer with hands-on experience in a variety of development and engineering positions. Willing to take ownership of core components. I have helped companies in developing greenfield product and maintain legacy systems to deliver value to millions of users.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer Amazon

05/2017 - Present

Working within a high tech team around the globe to launch amazon. AE/SA, develop/support MENA payment experience, migrate Souq.com instrument data and support amazon distributed services.

Website: www.amazon.com

Software Engineer-Java DeveloperPayfort

08/2016 - 05/2017

Working on an awesome start-up payment gateway. Build a restful APIs service to support business needs to provide a trusted e-payment solution allows customers to pay online!

Website: www.payfort.com

Software Engineer-Java DeveloperBlulogix

06/2014 - 07/2016

Working on a cloud billing platform for telecom operators. Build a Restful APIs service that's designed to enable service providers to capture new revenue opportunities and further improve customer service.

Website: www.blulogix.com

LEARNING

In continuous learning path

Believer in self-training, especially in the modern world, where constant learning is the best way for geeks to stay synchronized with rapidly evolving technology.

EDUCATION

 Software Engineering Hashemite University

2011 – 2014

SKILLS

Highly involved in understanding business requirements and translating it into a specific software design on E-commerce, E-payment, Fraud, accounting and promotions businesses.

Excellenth experience in backend development and design, Java, Node Js and Kotlin.

Good knowledge in front-end development React/AngularJs/Bootstrap.

Excellent experience in REST API design/develop and 3rd party integration(REST, SOAP).

Excellent experience in cloud computing (AWS) serverless, microservices and CI/CD.

Excellent experience in reporting using the jasper report engine.

Ability to work as individual or within a team to deliver results

Hands-on experience on software development methodologies Agile scrum and traditional waterfall.

LANGUAGES

Full Professional Proficiency

Arabic

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Coding

Boxing

Cars

Hiking

Spend time with family and friends